# **JOSHUA COX**

# Product Analyst | Full Stack Software Developer

Atlanta, GA

(615) 403-8575 | joshdcox50@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY + SKILLS**

Experienced IT professional with a demonstrated history of working in the healthcare tech industry. Passionate about the interconnectivity of business, analytics and technology. Comfortable working with distributed and remote teams. Skills include HTML/CSS, JavaScript, React, Bootstrap, Flexbox Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, Linux, Git/Github, Jira, MATLAB, RESTful API, Artiva, Cactus and debugging.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **DigitalCrafts - Full Stack Software Developer**

Certificate in Software Engineering | April 2019 - Present

- A top-rated coding bootcamp teaching the fundamentals of programming through an intensive classroom experience, transforming beginners into full-stack software engineers with cutting-edge skill sets.
- Covers full-stack web development. Emphasis on JavaScript, frameworks like React/Redux and server-side technologies including Node.js, Express, and PostgreSQL.
- Program will be complete in November 2019.

# The University of Tennessee - B.S. in Geology

Knoxville, TN | August 2013

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Hospital Corporation of America**, January 2015 - Present

#### Product Analyst - Enterprise Process Management and Support

May 2016 - Present

- Work closely with the development and operations teams to define product requirements and write user stories.
- Lead the cross-functional stakeholders in high-level troubleshooting and prioritization of bugs, negotiating tradeoffs, and collaboration across the development team.
- Serve as a point of escalation for the Provider Enrollment team, helping to remove barriers and roadblocks and navigate difficult or complex decisions.
- Partner with operations to validate problems and translate those into user stories + product requirements for our development team.
- Coordinate with QA team to test new enhancements.
- Assist in building and maintaining a delegated credentialing workflow.
- Maintain and monitor a financial risk analysis report to uncover sources of unknown monetary risk for our Accounting team.

# Team Lead for Medicaid - Provider Enrollment

September 2015 - May

2016

- Managed team's visibility, documentation and process tools
- Monitored all enrollment activities pertaining to Medicaid and ensured all work was completed in a timely manner.

• Provided guidance, oversight, and mentorship to the team

# **Enrollment Specialist for Medicaid - Provider Enrollment**

January 2015 - September 2015

- Oversaw and completed Medicaid enrollment for practices and their providers.
- Supported enrollment issues that impacted claims.

# Vanderbilt, August 2013 - August 2014

#### **Research Assistant**

- Observed and analyzed the glacial history of the central Transantarctic Mountains via cosmologically derived radionuclides from erratic rocks.
- Prepared rock samples for analysis using physical and chemical methods.

# **CERTIFICATIONS + TRAINING**

- SQL Certification
- Intro to UX Design General Assembly
- Effective Facilitator training
- The Odin Project Web Development 101